Q1. What is the result of the expression 5 + 3 * 2 in Java?
a. 16
b. 11
c. 13
d. 10
Answer: b. 11 (Multiplication has higher precedence than addition)

Q2. Which of the following is the correct operator for bitwise AND in Java?
a. &&
b. &
c. |
d. ||
Answer: b. & (Bitwise AND operator)

Q3. What is the result of the expression 10 / 3 in Java?
a. 3.33
b. 3
c. 4
d. 3.0
Answer: b. 3 (Integer division)

Q4. Which of the following is the ternary operator in Java?
a. ::
b. ?:
c. @
d. &
Answer: b. ?: (Ternary operator)

Q5. What is the result of the expression 7 % 3 in Java?
a. 1
b. 2
c. 3
d. 4
Answer: a. 1 (Modulus operator gives the remainder)

Q6. Which of the following operators is used to concatenate two strings in Java?
a. +
b. &
c. |
d. +=
Answer: a. + (String concatenation)

Q7. What is the result of the expression true && false in Java?
a. true
b. false
c. 0
d. 1
Answer: b. false (Logical AND)

Q8. Which of the following operators is used for logical OR in Java?
a. |
b. &&
c. ||
d. &
Answer: c. || (Logical OR)

Q9. Which of the following is the correct order of precedence (highest to lowest) in Java?
A. (), * / %, + -
B. + -, * / %, ()
C. * / %, (), + -
D. (), + -, * / %
Answer: A


Q10.Which operator is used to combine multiple conditions in an if statement in Java?
a. ||
b. &
c. &&
d. |
Answer: c. && (Logical AND)

Q11. Which operator is used to perform a logical NOT operation in Java?
a. ~
b. !
c. -
d. &
Answer: b. ! (Logical NOT operator)

Q12. What will be the result of the following code?
int x = 5;
int y = ++x * 10;
System.out.println(y);
a. 50
b. 60
c. 40
d. 10
Answer: b. 60 (++x increments x to 6 before the multiplication)

Q13. Which operator is used to compare two values for inequality in Java?
a. ==
b. =
c. !=
d. <>
Answer: c. != (Inequality operator)

Q14. What is the result of the following expression?

int x = 10;
int y = ++x + x++;
System.out.println(y);

A. 21
B. 22
C. 20
D. 23
Answer: B [++x is pre-increment  becomes 11, then x++ returns 11 and becomes 12 ,  11 + 11 = 22]

Q15. What is the result of the expression 10 % 4 in Java?
a. 2
b. 0
c. 4
d. 1
Answer: a. 2 (Modulus operator gives the remainder)

Q16. Which of the following is not a valid operator in Java?
a. >>>
b. &=
c. #
d. %
Answer: c. # (# is not a valid operator in Java)

Q17. What is the value of the expression true || false && true in Java?
a. true
b. false
c. null
d. 1
Answer: a. true (&& has higher precedence than ||)

Q18.What is the output.
int x = 5;
int y = 10;
System.out.println(x < y && y > x);

A. false
B. true
C. 0
D. Compilation error
Answer: B

Q19. Which of these operators has the lowest precedence?
A. *
B. +
C. =
D. &&
Answer: C [Assignment (=) has the lowest precedence.]


Q20. What is the result of the following expression if a = 5 and b = 3?
int result = a + (b * a) / b;
a. 5
b. 8
c. 10
d. 6
Answer: b. 8 ((b * a) / b is evaluated first, resulting in 5 + 3)

Q21.Which operator has the highest precedence in Java?
A. &&
B. *
C. ++
D. ()
Answer: D

Q22. Which operator is used to perform a bitwise OR operation in Java?
a. ||
b. |
c. &
d. ^
Answer: b. | (Bitwise OR operator)

Q23. What does the expression a *= b + 5 do in Java?
a. Sets a to a * b + 5
b. Sets a to a * (b + 5)
c. Sets a to a + b * 5
d. Sets a to a * b and adds 5
Answer: b. Sets a to a * (b + 5) (Compound assignment operator)

Q24. What is the result of the expression 5 & 3 in Java?
a. 7
b. 1
c. 5
d. 3
Answer: b. 1 (Bitwise AND)

Q25. Which operator is used to check if two object references point to the same object in memory in Java?
a. ==
b. equals
c. instanceof
d. !=
Answer: a. == (Reference comparison)

Q26. What does the operator += do in Java?
a. It adds the right operand to the left operand and assigns the result to the left operand.
b. It subtracts the right operand from the left operand and assigns the result to the left operand.
c. It multiplies the left operand by the right operand and assigns the result to the left operand.
d. It divides the left operand by the right operand and assigns the result to the left operand.
Answer: a. It adds the right operand to the left operand and assigns the result to the left operand.

Q27. What will be the result of the following code?
int x = 5;
int y = x++;
System.out.println(y);
a. 6
b. 4
c. 5
d. 0
Answer: c. 5 (x++ is post-increment, so y is assigned x's value before incrementing)

Q28. Which of the following operators is used to access a class’s member variables 
or methods in Java?
a. ->
b. .
c. ::
d. :
Answer: b. . (Dot operator)

Q29. What is the output of this code?
int a = 5;
int b = 10;
int c = a + b * 2;
System.out.println(c);

A. 30
B. 20
C. 25
D. 35
Answer: C
[b * 2 = 20, then a + 20 = 25]

Q30. Which operator is used to combine multiple conditions in an if statement in Java?
a. ||
b. &
c. &&
d. |
Answer: c. && (Logical AND)

